When social media, “boy will be boys,” and vigilante justice
collide, Steubenville, Ohio will never be the same.
Roll Red Roll is a documentary film directed by Nancy Schwartzman.
At a 2012 pre-season high-school football party in Steubenville, Ohio, a young
woman was raped by members of the beloved high school football team.
The aftermath exposed an entire culture of complicity—and Roll Red Roll maps out the roles that
peer pressure, denial, sports machismo, and social media each played in the tragedy.
Self, played by Mark Cole.
Self, played by Anthony Craig.
Self, played by Rachel Dissell.
Self, played by Alexandria Goddard.
Self, played by Marianne Hemmeter.
Self, played by Walter Madison.
Roll Red Roll is a 2018 American documentary film,
directed and produced by Nancy Schwartzman.
It follows the Steubenville High School rape case.
The film had its world premiere at the Tribeca Film Festival on April 22, 2018.
It was released in a limited release on March 22, 2019, by Together
Films, prior to its debut on POV on PBS on June 17, 2019.
The film explores themes of rape, woman director, rape culture.